# NICHOLAS HERRICK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER 

● AURORA, COLORADO 80013 

• (720)-299-9354

#### • DETAILS •

19157 E Harvard Dr Aurora, Colorado 80013 (720)-299-9354 nick@nicholasherrick.com

#### • LINKS •

Portfolio

**LinkedIn** 

**Github** 

### • SKILLS •

JavaScript

HTML & CSS

MySQL

MongoDB

Node

React

Redux

SASS

Next

Git

API MVC

ООР

Documentation

Communication

**Critical Thinking** 

Complex Problem Solving

**Creative Thinking** 

**Time Management** 

Leadership & Cooperation

Fast & Adaptive Learning

Teaching

Microsoft Office

Windows OS

Mac OS

Healthcare (operating room)

### PROFILE

Software Engineer & Web Developer with experience in the Denver area. Certified in Full Stack Development from the University of Denver. Able to build and manage Full Stack applications. Primarily work with everything JavaScript. Proficient with React & Node and SQL & NoSQL databases. Aware of the importance of writing clear, easy to understand code in an organized and uniform process.

## **★** OBJECTIVE

To obtain a full time position as a software developer, developing and maintaining software

#### **★** PROJECTS

#### Mural Map

Demo | Github

- Mural Map gives users an interactive map with markers to visit previously discovered murals or add new ones to the database (with pictures).
- Challenges: Implementing image uploads, managing markers with the Maps API.

#### StaySafe

Demo | Github

- StaySafe provides users multiple ways to call for help while sharing location with the press of a button.
- Group project, I created the wireframe, documentation and helped create front-end components, back end api logic, styling and debugging
- Challenges: Creating mobile UI & UX, implementing friend requests through email.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Front End Developer at Bluejestic, (remote)

December 2020 — Present

Create Front-End components using React, Redux, Next, Sass, GraphQL, etc. Attend weekly agile stand up meetings. Coordinate implementations with CEO & other developers.

- Became a productive member of the Front End team in less than a month.
- · Created documentation to improve new developer experience
- · Refactored code base to improve scalability, dryness, and reusability

## **Teaching Assistant at Trilogy Education Services, (remote)**

December 2020 — Present

Assist students & instructor with coding curriculum & lessons inside and outside of class. Host a weekly office hours sessions with students.

• Mentored students to improve understanding of complex programming concepts.

### Freelance Developer at Starlight Foundry, Denver, CO

April 2020 — December 2020

Consult clients on technical needs, design & build applications from scratch based on client's needs, launch, host, maintain and update client applications.

• Launched my own small scale Freelance business in the Denver area.

## EDUCATION

## **Bootcamp Certificate, University of Denver**

2019 - 2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

High School, Denver School of Science and Technology

2009 - 2013